

## **CONTACT**

+44 (0) 7918 756467

+49 (0) 15171257736

matthewsangharad@gmail.com

www.angharadmatthews.com

# **EDUCATION**

## 2016 - 2018

MA Devised Theatre and Performance Practices Arthaus Berlin/Rose Bruford London

## 2008 - 2009

Dance Training Program Rubicon Dance Cardiff

#### 2002 - 2005

BA (hons) Theatre Design
The Royal Welsh Collage of Music
and Drama

## 2001 - 2002

BTEC Diploma Foundation Studies in Art and Design Pontypridd Collage, Wales

#### **DATE OF BIRTH**

03.08.1983

# **Angharad Matthews**

THEATRE DESIGNER, PERFORMER, PRACTITIONER

#### **PROFILE**

Welsh Artist Angharad Matthews is a versatile freelance designer, performer and practitioner, working within the field of theatre, dance, film, and circus. She has worked extensively throughout Wales and Europe with companies including National Theatre Wales, National Dance Company Wales, NoFitState Circus, Gothenburg Opera, Volcano, Frantic Assembly, Company of Sirens and National Youth Theatre Wales.

Angharad was a founding member of Nurture Creative Dance Theatre based at Rubicon Dance, where she began developing her choreographic process with 'The Audition' funded by ACW.

Angharad now resides in Berlin where she completed her MA with Arthaus Berlin/Rose Bruford. And is continuing to develop her ongoing practice, and creative collaborations.

# **EXPERIENCE**

2005 - Present - Theatre Designer/Maker/Supervisor - International

2008 - Present - Performer/Actress - International

2016 - Present - Child carer and educator - Private tuition Berlin

2019 - Present - Physical theatre training workshop leader - Berlin

2019 - Present - Costume Assistant - Odile Hautemulle - Berlin

#### **Productions**

Company of Sirens - Wales - Director Chris Durnall

- Souvenirs of a killing (2020) Designer/Performer
- Twelve Cabins Twelve Vacancies (2019) Designer/Performer
- The Creature (2019) Designer/Performer

Uluak Teatro - Basque Country/Berlin

Maite (2019) - Costume Designer

Julia Van De hoff - - English Theatre Berlin/Ufer studios Berlin

Percephone (2019) - Deviser/performer

Cat Gerrard - Berlin/Basque Country

• Some where maybe here (2018 - 2019) - Costume Designer

Gothenburg Opera - Sweden - Choreographer Roy Assaf

• Sacre (2017) - Costume Designer

Nurture Creative Dance Theatre - Wales

• The Audition (2015 - 2016) - Director/Choreographer

#### **WORKSHOPS ATTENDED**

Acting for camera - The workshop Cardiff (2016)

Butoh Space Dance - Tetsuro Fukuhara Wales/Tokyo (2015)

## **LANGUAGES**

English (First language)

German (basic understanding)

#### **SKILLS**

- Patience
- Adaptability
- Creativity
- Team Work
- Communication
- Positive attitude

#### **OTHER INTERESTS**

- Yoga
- Running
- Swimming
- Arts and crafts
- Reading

# **REFERENCES**

## **Theatre**

Sean Crowley Head of Design RWCMD sean.crowley@rwcmd.ac.uk

Thomas Prattki, Founder and director Arthaus Berlin welcome@arthaus.berlin

## Working with children

Jessica Hellman -Actress/Acting Coach lamdacentreberlin@gmail.com

## **EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

National theatre Wales -

- Mission Control (2019) Costume Designer
- Before I leave (2016) Costume Designer
- 150 (2015) Costume Designer
- The Gathering (2014) Costume Supervisor
- In water I'm weightless (2012) Co costume designer/Supervisor
- Little dogs (2012) Costume Supervisor
- The Soul Exchange (2011) Costume Supervisor

Gwyn Emberton Dance - Wales

• Shadows of a quiet society (2016) - Costume and Set designer

National Dance Company Wales -

- Tundra (2017) Costume Designer
- Profundis' (2016) Costume Designer
- Alternative Roots (2013) Costume Design Supervisor

Walk the Plank - Wales Millennium Centre

• Ar Waith Ar Daith (2015) - Costume design/ Aerial Performer

Nofit state Circus - Director Firenza Guidi

- Bianco (2012 2015) Co Costume Designer
- Tabu (2008 2010) Co Costume Designer
- Immortal (2007) Co Costume Designer

#### TV and Commercial

Smarva - (2020) Berlin - Commercial Allianz - Arthur Mebius – (2019) Berlin - Advertising Cinemagraph Flux FM Radio (2019) Berlin - Voice over Stellan Stephenson (2019) Berlin/Stockholm - Advertising Photos

(more detailed experience list 2005 - 2020 available on request)

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Directing/ Teaching/ Workshop leading
- Costume Design/ Making/ Pattern Cutting
- Hand and Machine sewing/ Applique & Textile art/ Dying and Distressing
- Research/ Sourcing /Buying
- Set Design/ Scenic Painting/ Scale Model Making
- Acting for Theatre/ Film/ Tv
- Devised theatre/ Collaborative theatre making
- Puppetry/ Mask work/ Clown/ Improvisation
- Stilt walking/ Street theatre/ Aerial Hoop
- Dance Theatre/ Choreography/ Movement direction